<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Steganography on ChaGu CTF</title><link>https://chagu.org/tags/steganography/</link><description>Recent content in Steganography on ChaGu CTF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chagu.org/tags/steganography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Interstellar (150pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for2/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Dr. Cooper, on another one of his endless journeys encounter a mysterious planet. However when he tried to land on it, the ship gave way and he was left stranded on the planet. Desperate for help, he relays a message to the mothership containing the details of the people with him. Their HyperPhotonic transmission is 10 times the speed of light, so there is no delay in the message.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Lost Friends (300pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg3/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Moana and her friends were out on a sea voyage, spending their summer joyously. Unfortnately, they came across Charybdis, the sea monster. Charybdis, furious over having unknown visitors, wreaked havoc on their ship. The ship was lost. Luckily, Moana survived, and she was swept to a nearby island. But, since then, she has not seen her friends. Moana has come to you for help.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: New Avenger (300pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg4/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : The Avengers are scouting for a new member. They have travelled all around the world, looking for suitable candidates for the new position. Finally, they have found the perfect candidate. But, they are in a bad situation. They do not know who the guy is behind the mask. Can you help the Avengers to uncover the identity of the person behind the mask ?</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Star Wars (100pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_steg1/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Don't search blindly. Look carefully and you will find what you are looking for. Hint! This challenge is specially made for blind persons :P File : star-wars.jpg Solution: Nothing speacial with the image when you look at it:
Running strings reveal a bit encoded thing with 54 bits:
100110 101010 101010 111010 100110 1010101 011101 010100 11110 Since the hint mention that it was made for a blind person I look you &amp;ldquo;blind alphabet&amp;rdquo; on google and i found that they are a part of a six-bit character code called Braille codes.</description></item></channel></rss>