<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on ChaGu CTF</title><link>https://chagu.org/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on ChaGu CTF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chagu.org/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VolgaCTF 2017: Bloody Feedback - web 100</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/volgactf-2017-quals_bloody_feedback_web_100/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/volgactf-2017-quals_bloody_feedback_web_100/</guid><description>Author: @mjdubell
Bloody Feedback Send your feedback at bloody-feedback.quals.2017.volgactf.ru DO. NOT. USE. SQLMAP Otherwise your IP will be banned The challenge basically has two functions, 1) Send feedback and 2) view the status of the sent feedback. There is also page that cotains &amp;ldquo;Top Messages&amp;rdquo; which is the feedback people send in. When you send feedback you get a token back which you can use to see if the feedback has been processed or not.</description></item><item><title>VolgaCTF 2017: Share Point - web 200</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/volgactf-2017-quals_share_point_web_200/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/volgactf-2017-quals_share_point_web_200/</guid><description>Author: @mjdubell
Share Point Look! I wrote a good service for sharing your files with your friends, enjoy) share-point.quals.2017.volgactf.ru The challenge begun by signing in to the control panel by simply entering random account details. Once logged in you had the ability to upload files and share them with an other user. Since the site only had one functionality, uploading files, I assumed the goal had to be to upload a web shell and find the flag on the file system.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Give The Guy (100pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_web1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_web1/</guid><description>By: ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Hacker G has a website. Can you use it to decipher this cipher text ? Cipher text :- dobrjtuojxagbqhd Link : http://139.59.62.216/give_the_guy/ NOTE :- Please enclose the flag in the format pragyanctf{&amp;lt;flag&amp;gt;}. Solution: After brute forcing the challenge, probing for hidden directories/files, it turned out that if you simply run Affine-cipher on the ciphertext, you get the flag&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Supreme Leader (150pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_web2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_web2/</guid><description>By: ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : North Korea reportedly has a bioweapon in the making. Hack into their database and steal it. Link : http://139.59.62.216/supreme_leader NOTE :- Please enclose the flag in the format pragyanctf{&amp;lt;flag&amp;gt;}. Solution: Using burpsuite we could notice that there are two cookies getting set.
The first one does not apper when looking at the browser cookies because its getting over written have the value:
2541d938b0a58946090d7abdde0d3890_b8e2e0e422cae4838fb788c891afb44
Using hashkiller we got:</description></item><item><title>Insomni'hack teaser: Smarttomcat (web 50)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_smarttomcat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_smarttomcat/</guid><description>For this challenge, you are supposed to enter the correct coordinates to find the robot cat.
For these types of challenges, I like using burp suite in order to record and modify HTTP requests. The following request was recorded when entering some random values.
POST /index.php HTTP/1.1 Host: smarttomcat.teaser.insomnihack.ch User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10.12; rv:50.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/50.0 Accept: */* Accept-Language: en-US,en;q=0.5 Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate Content-Type: application/x-www-form-urlencoded; charset=UTF-8 X-Requested-With: XMLHttpRequest Referer: http://smarttomcat.</description></item><item><title>Insomni'hack teaser: The Great Escape I (forensics 50)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_the_great_escape_1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_the_great_escape_1/</guid><description>The challenge was in the forensic category and all we got was a .pcap-file to analyze.
Recon We opened the file in wireshark and started analyzing. While looking through the packets we recognized that almost the whole communication was encrypted. To get an overview over the used protocols we looked at the Protocol Hierarchy (Statistics -&amp;gt; Protocol Hierarchy). We see SMTP and FTP, sweet!
Extraction We filtered for ftp-data packets and followed the TCP stream (Follow -&amp;gt; TCP Stream) which revealed that bob was uploading his private key in plaintext.</description></item><item><title>Insomni'hack teaser: The Great Escape II (web 200)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_the_great_escape_2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_the_great_escape_2/</guid><description>We didn&amp;rsquo;t solve this challenge but we were working on it for quite some time. This writeup is based on https://jiulongw.github.io/post/insomnihack-2017-the-great-escape/#part-ii-web-200-pts, what we should have done.
What we did correct We found the link https://ssc.teaser.insomnihack.ch/ from the .pcap file during The Great Escape 1. We also had the username and password for the rogue account (rogue:rogue) which we could sign in to. If we visit https://ssc.teaser.insomnihack.ch/files we could see a list of uploaded files.</description></item></channel></rss>