<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Misc on ChaGu CTF</title><link>https://chagu.org/tags/misc/</link><description>Recent content in Misc on ChaGu CTF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chagu.org/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Game of Fame (50pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_cr1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_cr1/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : p xasc. a zdmik qtng. yiy uist. easc os iye iq trmkbumk. gwv wolnrg kaqcs vi rlr. NOTE :- Please enclose the flag in the format pragyanctf{&amp;lt;flag&amp;gt;}. Hint! The seven star-studded Pragyan walks into the hall of fame. Boom! Hint! Robert Sedgewick Solution: Playing around with the cipher text on this site I noticed somthing interesting when using the Vigenere Cipher. And that was that it suggest that they key might be PRAQJAN.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Interstellar (150pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for2/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Dr. Cooper, on another one of his endless journeys encounter a mysterious planet. However when he tried to land on it, the ship gave way and he was left stranded on the planet. Desperate for help, he relays a message to the mothership containing the details of the people with him. Their HyperPhotonic transmission is 10 times the speed of light, so there is no delay in the message.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Look Harder (50pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for1/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : There are rumours that in the Great Sahara Desert, a great treasure has been buried deep inside the ground, but the map for the exact location of the treasure over the years, has not been preserved properly. You have got hold of the map, but it looks nothing more than a plain white sheet of paper. Can you make sense out of it ?</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: Shane and the binary files (100pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_bin2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_bin2/</guid><description>Challenge Description : Shane is a part of one of the teams in the FBI, which is currently handling a very weird cyber crime case. As a part of the investigation, Shane was asked to analyze a series of binary files, one of which is known to give out a password. Shane got the files in a zip file named &amp;quot;parallel.zip&amp;quot;. Could you help him do it ? NOTE :- Please enclose the flag in the format pragyanctf{&amp;lt;flag&amp;gt;}.</description></item><item><title>Pragyan CTF 2017: The Karaboudjan (150pts)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/pragyan-ctf-2017_for3/</guid><description>By: [noras] from ChalmersCTF
Challenge Description : Captain Haddock is on one of his ship sailing journeys when he gets stranded off the coast of North Korea. He finds shelter off a used nuke and decides to use the seashells to engrave a message on a piece of paper. Decrypt the message and save Captain Haddock. -&amp;gt;-.&amp;gt;-.---.--&amp;gt;-.&amp;gt;.&amp;gt;+.--&amp;gt;--..++++. .+++. .-&amp;gt;-.-&amp;gt;-.++++++++++.+&amp;gt;+++.++.-[-&amp;gt;+++&amp;lt;]&amp;gt;+.+++++.++++++++++..++++[-&amp;gt;+++&amp;lt;]&amp;gt;.--.-&amp;gt;--.&amp;gt;. NOTE :- Please enclose the flag in the format pragyanctf{&amp;lt;flag&amp;gt;}. File : clue.</description></item><item><title>NullCon 2017: Misc2 [300]</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/nullcon_2017_misc2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/nullcon_2017_misc2/</guid><description>Challenge: &amp;ldquo;Got an artefact file to be analysed. Can you please help me find the hidden data ?&amp;rdquo; and there is a file attached
The first thing I did was to check what type of files by running file and binwalk on it
root@kali:~/Downloads# file artefact artefact: XZ compressed data root@kali:~/Downloads# binwalk artefact DECIMAL HEXADECIMAL DESCRIPTION -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 0 0x0 xz compressed data So the next step is to decompress it as following:</description></item><item><title>Insomni'hack teaser: Cryptoquizz (crypto/misc 50)</title><link>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_cryptoquiz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 11:22:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chagu.org/posts/insomnihack_teaser_2017_cryptoquiz/</guid><description>This was an interesting challange. You started by connecting with telnet to the server specified in the challenge description. Once connected, a question was asked: What is the birth year of [known cryptographer]? You had 2 seconds to react before the server disconnected you. Once you connected again, the server asked the same question but for a different person. I begun connecting over and over again to see if there was a pattern or if the selection of people was small.</description></item></channel></rss>